

SAMEER SAYYED

Sales & Marketing

ABOUT ME

Enthusiastic and industrious professional having around 8 years of work experience with strong **Training** & acumen looking forward to work for an organization where I can fully utilize my skills contributing to its growth as well as take on responsibilities for new progression of my career.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

B2C Sales ****

Digital Marketing ***

B2B Sales ***

SOFT SKILLS

Leadership *****

Interpersonal ****

Analytical ****

Innovative ****

Energetic *****

COMPUTER PROFICIENCY

MS Office ★★★★◆

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

CONTACT INFORMATION

*****: +91 - 7299978689

⊠: sayyed.benz@gmail.com

ជ: Triplicane, Chennai– 600<u>005</u>

PERSONAL INFORMATION

± (DOB): 19th October 1989

(Marital Status): Married

BACKGROUND

EDUCATION

2007-11 – Bachelors in Management Studies from VIT, Mumbai **2005/07** – Completed **SSC** (Class X) and **HSC** (Class XII) from Anjuman Islam School and Rizvi School & College, Mumbai respectively.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Education Counselor at Sharekhan Education India from January 2020 - Present

- Trained client (Service/Business Profile) and guide them how to use software and following up with the existing ones regarding company services related to financial education and trading.
- Updating information of prospects in the company CRM.
- Up selling and cross selling advanced company products.
- Meeting (face to face) with the prospects to understand their needs and counsel them accordingly on the most relevant company products/services.

Assistant Manager (Sales Trainer) at KLN Motors from December 2018 – December 2019

- Trained sales executives about Product knowledge to hone their communication skills and personality traits.
- **Supervised** entire **sales team** by giving them direction and motivating them to achieve sales goals.
- Formulated **digital marketing strategies** to develop and maintain long term digital connection with customers.
- Monitored and measured performance of digital marketing campaigns that were run on various social media platforms like Facebook etc. using web analytic tools.
- Brainstormed ideas for content marketing & website update.

Sr. Sales Advisor at VST Titanium Motors (Mercedez Benz) from December 2017 – November 2018

- Achieved sales targets for passenger car division and maximized sales revenues by negotiating with customers.
- Analyzed competitor behavior and subsequently brainstormed counter sales strategies.
- Built strong client relations to gain their loyalty.

Sales Executive turned Team Leader at Khivraj Motors from October 2013 - November 2017

- Spearheaded team sales executives as Team Lead (2016-17) for premium car segment.
- Guided sales executives by helping them prepare official travel plans and achieve sales targets.
- Worked as sales executive during the initial 3 years (2013-16)
 where primary role was to communicate features and
 benefits of all vehicle types to customers.
- Awarded as star performer for 12 times during the tenure.

Sales Executive at Kapico Motors India Pvt. Ltd. from August 2012 - September 2013

- Sold cars to SME's and corporate clients (B2B Sales).
- Formulated client retention strategies by understanding their needs.